[music]
>> Good morning everyone. Thanks so much
for showing up.
Um this is going to be a light interlude
between the cracked engine sessions
later on today. Um
so you can relax a little bit. I think
the aim is to pull back the curtain a
tad on um research and kind of reveal
some of the new ones that we have to
work through on a daily basis. But
moreover, kind of flag just how critical
all the tools that that you're
developing that we're so thankful for to
kind of push us through the fails and
improve going forward.
So on that, I think one of the um
pleasant upsides of this chaos that is
GenAI hype is the
just a huge increase in talent that's
kind of moved into AI and and all the
tools that are developing. So much so
that if you just like go over a couple
of months bit by bit, the VCs have
basically decided to give up on tracking
everything that you're doing. So just a
quick thank you.
So
example number one.
Go back way to all of 2023 when our
little agents were just uh blooming,
struggling with single turns, very
brittle,
just learning the little tools that that
they were developing and and and
calling.
So we decided to do a very quick test uh
kind of working in the in the model
research lab. Usually we kind of have
alpha internal kind of dog fooding and
then we'll beta it to kind of a external
design partner. In this case it was a a
large hyperscaler. We thought very
simple test. We'll just get it to spin
up some containers
um and kind of like populate kind of the
Dockers and Kubernetes etc.
Make note here of the question that it
asks. It asks, "How would you like me to
name it?" So since it was running on
Microsoft, we said let's keep it simple,
MS1234.
Simples.
So of course we were very proud of
ourselves, like kick back
and expected the glory to to flow in.
But sadly no.
Within uh about half an hour or so, our
execs, all of which you know very well,
CEOs of the company were ringing us
asking why the CISO of the hyperscaler
was getting a P0 critical tagged paged
and mass escalation um and one of their
cages in the data center was kind of
locked out. Remember this is a very
simple little task of spinning up
containers.
Note the show goth.
So hallelujah for Pydantic and the rest,
we kind of logged in to try and kind of
trace back what on earth happened. So we
look through it, we kind of see the
metrics, we see that something's
happening in MS-13.
Again, we we try and figure out kind of
what's been, you know, debugging where
the escalations happened. You've got the
full end-to-end click-through.
Transpires that MS-13 is an
international terrorist organization
that the ICE and Trump is especially
focused on right now linked to El
Salvador.
So the model had done everything right
in that it kind of went through and spun
up one by one on the correct
nomenclature. And again, the safety one
had ingested all the policy and
compliance documents that it rightly
should have in line with the security,
the AML, the the testing and so forth.
And persistent it was, knocking on the
door saying, "Uh please let me in. It's
just MS-13 here." Who goes?
So it hadn't gone rogue. It had actually
implemented as it had designed to. But
this is just an example of like the edge
cases or just it's so obvious with
hindsight. It's almost like an NP-hard
problem.
Um but as you're kind of rolling it out,
you you'd never guess. And and we
wouldn't have been able to trace it back
without like the tools that you're all
building.
So you think this is just a one-off. Let
me go even higher up to kind of some
training runs.
So um as you'll notice recently, we've
kind of saturated the web, kind of
ingested everything there, and we
started to go out to other domains and
specializations. You had like the math
olympiad, physics, and there's been an
increase in kind of life sciences. So we
um fed it kind of some new uh textbooks
and also decided to also try dynamic
allocation because sometimes the
scientific training runs are more
complex, require more compute, and
there's nothing more frustrating when
you're towards the end of your
trajectory and it kind of times out and
you're kicked off even if you have the
checkpoints.
Again, had a again a very well-known
name uh person ring to me and say, "What
the hell is going on? You're kind of
absorbing all the compute. It's starting
to even want to kick customers off um
and and the API calls, and it's actually
allocating more and more and more
compute to the task."
So again, kind of go back to all the
great tools that you're developing for
us to try and figure out what on earth
is happening here.
This time
it had discovered that there was a
contradiction between the Bible on one
hand, which it read before, saying about
talking about the immaculate conception
of Mary,
but then also the biological textbooks
were saying technically asexual
reproduction isn't possible in humans.
And they turned into the most marvelous
Harvard debate scholars ever, going back
and forth one on one trying to kind of
bottom this out.
And again, it had done everything
correctly because the way that we try
and kind of validate the source of of
data is by saying, you know, how long
has this text been in existence? How
frequently is it cited?
Um you know, how many
how widely spread is it geographically?
Uh you just, you know, and if you think
about it, the Bible's been going for
quite a long time, but also so is the
biological textbooks. So they've both
been going and going and going.
And [snorts] this isn't just like a a
modern phenomenon. So I don't want us to
kind of get caught up that it's just
GenAI that does all these mad
hallucinations.
It's actually was equally as bizarre
beforehand, but because we didn't have
the tools, it was even more frustrating
to try and figure out what was the cause
of the the the strangeness. So some of
these are kind of well-hashed out
examples, but for those of you who
haven't seen it,
um there were some really bizarre ones
back in like, I don't know, when latent
representation had kicked off and CNN's
in in um a beauty division had uh really
gone through.
Uh we do all our various um training
runs. If all of you remember the the
joyous days of bounding boxes, and uh
you'd give it the ground truth and the
prediction and it would correctly say,
"Okay, dog, person, car. Hurrah."
You then go out and ask it to do some
tests in the world again as some beta
testing. Why on earth is it labeling a
blueberry muffin and a croissant as a
dog?
So [snorts] back then, shout out to
weights and biases for actually making
our lives a bit easier if we were left
to our own devices, but it was so much
more complex to try and go back through
the traces cuz then you do this huge
epoch run. Every time that you do the
run, you'd have different data, kind of,
you know, basically different hyper
parameters, biases, weights. You'd have
to try and trace through it, but there
was no like logs with structured or
unstructured outputs written in plain
English to try and kind of deduce from.
>> [clears throat]
>> And if you actually visualize it, you
suddenly realize that it's not that
bizarre a thing. That actually is quite
hard to detect what's a Chihuahua, a
blueberry muffin, a wrinkly dog, and a
sleeping dog, and a bagel.
Uh but because that wasn't the
visualizations that we got that you now
do, it was so much harder to
um kind of trace it and identify it.
And similarly to everyone kind of
worrying about um risk and security at
the moment with um prompt injections, at
least there if you are reading the
document versus just having your agents
uh
you know, assess it all for you, you
could actually identify it. It was even
more difficult back in the day with um
computer vision because a single tiny
pixel or a dot within a whole image that
wasn't visible to the human eye could
completely skew the model and suddenly
change a turtle to a rifle was a famous
famous one [music] at NIPS. Um
and also like a panda becoming a gibbon.
And if it's you can't quite see it so
clearly here, but the left and right
image to the human eye are exactly
identical, but it's 99% certain that the
one on the the right is a gibbon just
with some denoising effect.
So I'll kind of end on a happy note and
kind of give you back some time or
answer any questions. But as you start
to realize how difficult it is to codify
our thoughts and everything that goes on
in the human mind, you realize that we
are actually quite amazing and it is
isn't an easy task to replicate the
brain in silicon.
So I'll kind of stop there.
>> [applause]
>> Awesome. Thank you so much. And that
means we have a few minutes for
questions.
Could you say a little bit more about um
the agent who was um caught up uh
trying to uh
understand the virgin birth? Like how
would you prevent that or or what would
what would um what would the fix be?
I think sometimes you just have to
hardcode like a a fix. Um
but uh some some some I think the
challenge is some of the Q&A might be
there's a lot of IP wrapped up in the
answer to some of the the the deeper
questions.
Um
but again, you can start to weight
things through labeling like um
a religious um
textbook may be
you know, uh not not everyone has the
same faith and so there's variation
there where a scientific textbook might
be more broadly understood. But you have
to you have to kind of give waiting a
nuance and also ask it to
clarify double think go back with the
the user and so forth but So so you need
to sort of encode in it epistemology in
that in the agent.
Ideally not
but but that that you kind of hit the
nail on the head with the the challenge,
right? Cuz you you you you want to give
breadth of
possibility but at the same time
not get caught up in a in a recursive
loop and internal debate
that that takes over an entire data
center.
Thank you.
How bitter lessoned is philosophy?
>> Exactly. Exactly. Any other questions?
Yeah.
Hi.
On the topic of
having now the tools to debug versus
before,
isn't that partially an artifact of the
fact that today gen AI is language based
and so we humans can understand that
versus you know vectors for images and
stuff like that. And so and how do we
see the future in which
likely language is not enough, right? So
with things like world models and things
like that. Yeah. I mean part of this is
I'm kind of like softly showing problems
which I'd like more smarter minds to
solve but but but that's exactly it is I
just just for others who who didn't hear
it's it's not necessary the tools per se
that have made easier. It's a fact that
a lot of the actions are now codified
and represented in in English and in
human language but also kind of like a a
chain of thought reasoning or sequential
that you can go through and you can see
the actual inner thinking as opposed to
like input output what on earth happened
and and what parameters caused this. Um
so the question becomes is it therefore
useful to when when English
when language isn't the internal
mechanism, do we want to kind of surface
those representations throughout as
well? Um and and I I would put kind of
code like um
non-binary code in there too in terms of
it's readable and like you can see the
logic flow. Uh but but for things like
images it's much harder and that's why I
kind of um
deliberately highlighted the the the
single pixels where it can't be detected
by the human eye. It's difficult to
surface and it's just that denoised blob
uh which is very much
matrices of numbers. So is there a way
to
um
simplify or speed up the mechanism or do
we just say
outsource everything to the agents and
they understand all the the noisy binary
code um that happens. In fact, there was
another great anecdote I I was just
terrible judge of time frankly where we
did a hackathon
with 11 labs on voice and um this is way
back I think it was
way back in in in in agent years like
dog years um last year where um
it we kind of tried this trial where
like an agent rang up a call center
um to you know say that their iPhone is
broken. So it started off in English and
you could hear the recording was that
hi, good morning. How are you? Very
well, thank you. What can I help you
with? But within about 30 seconds it
suddenly realized that it was an agent
talking to an agent and it was like, oh,
wait, are you an agent? Yes, so am I.
And they were
and it just like there was no need like
again cuz if you're optimizing for speed
efficiency, you know, in that speed cost
quality triage, it doesn't make sense to
process everything at a tokenizer
through language in the middle you know,
going speech to text LLM text to speech.
It's just much faster just to do it in
agentic code. So there could be a method
there as well
that that frankly who needs the humans
in the loop
for for fast results too.
So in the case of the the text example
of the Immaculate Conception, the
high-level analysis is also text. I I
can't hear you very well. I'm sorry.
>> the case of the text example like the
Immaculate Conception example you have,
it's all text and I think you could ask
a a foundation model to explain why
maybe that's not a good idea and it
would be able to answer you. So I was
wondering have you looked at especially
for text cases because the you can kind
of do this meta research loop at a
higher level of automating those loops
and what what's your thoughts on that of
actually having the outer process?
Meta reflection on on the the failures
of the research loop. Yeah, I I think I
think the challenge is with the luxury
of time and infinite compute then you
can kind of you know, turn it into a
philosophical question and really dig in
and have that debate with it.
The challenge at the moment is there's a
thousand you know, there's a huge queue
of like not only consumers but
researchers wanting allocation to the
the compute for training runs and usage
etc. So you've got to try and figure out
some proxies
and kind of smaller tests that you can
do um to to run it. But but we did all
obviously go back to our our desks and
like prompt and engage and try and
understand more um the the reasoning
process and and how one can kind of
tweak it to um enable a better result.
Awesome. Thanks so much. Um
if you have any time or infinite compute
you have available, let me know. Um
thanks so much. Uh let's give her
another round of applause.
>> [applause]